<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="important" xreflabel="Important Information">
  <?dbhtml filename="important.html"?>

  <title>Important Information</title>

  <para>
    BLFS has more information regarding compilation, /usr vs /usr/local,
    boot scripts, etc. at
    <ulink url="&blfs-svn;/introduction/important.html"/>.
    Unlike this book, this would be a chapter in BLFS.
    A lot of that information has been omitted as this book is more linear
    and doesn't follow how BLFS follows. However, we will cover some bases
    here.
  </para>

  <sect2>
    <title>OpenGL</title>

    <para>
      There are two main OpenGL vendors on linux: Mesa and libglvnd. BLFS
      installs Mesa as the vendor. GLFS installs libglvnd as the vendor. This
      book mainly sees OpenGL in general and most packages work just fine.
      However, some are known to require fixes, either simple or too elaborate.
      They require extra resources to test, which the team behind this book
      does not have. So Mesa's OpenGL implementations are not supported. As a
      starting point, you can see <phrase revision="sysv"><ulink
      url="&lfs-website;/slfs/view/12.4/">SLFS 12.4</ulink></phrase>
      <phrase revision="systemd"><ulink
      url="&lfs-website;/slfs/view/12.4-systemd/">SLFS 12.4</ulink></phrase>
      and see how to go about fixing what is broken. See <ulink
      url="&glfs-website;/core/aboutgl.html">GLFS: About OpenGL</ulink>
      for more information about why support for Mesa's OpenGL implementations
      have been dropped from both this book and GLFS.
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Building software</title>

    <para>
      Building software on SLFS is identical to how it's done in the
      LFS books. It goes without saying firstmost that you should have
      <envar>MAKEFLAGS</envar> set to save yourself a lot of time. This is
      useful for the <command>make</command> utility to use the amount of
      threads that you both want and have.
    </para>

<screen><userinput>export MAKEFLAGS='-jx'</userinput></screen>

    <para>
      Replace <option>x</option> with the amount of threads you have.
      You can check the amount of threads you have with:
    </para>

<screen><userinput>grep processor /proc/cpuinfo</userinput></screen>

    <important>
      <para>
        Make sure that you have enough RAM for your system!
        A general method is having 2.5G per thread that is thrown at
        <command>make</command>. For instance, if you want to use 6 threads,
        multiply 6 by 2.5 (which is 15), then make sure you have 15G of RAM.
        If you don't have that RAM, try and limit the threads you throw at
        <command>make</command>.
      </para>
    </important>

  </sect2>

</sect1>
