<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="important" xreflabel="Important Information">
  <?dbhtml filename="important.html"?>

  <title>Important Information</title>

  <para>
    BLFS has more information regarding compilation, /usr vs /usr/local,
    boot scripts, etc. at 
    <ulink url="&blfs-svn;/introduction/important.html"/>.
    Unlike this book, this would be a chapter in BLFS.
    A lot of that information has been omitted as this book is more linear
    and doesn't follow how BLFS follows. However, we will cover some bases
    here.
  </para>

  <sect2>
    <title>Stability</title>

    <para>
      This book is in a constant flux of updates, including package updates,
      and can be akin to the BLFS Git version. Right now, there is no stable
      version of LFS QOL. This won't cause issues usually as packages in this
      book do not show up in any of the LFS books, but it is something to keep
      in mind.
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Init System</title>

    <para revision="sysv">
      This version of this book is meant for SysV/non-Systemd LFS systems,
      although there is a Systemd version of this book. However, due to Github
      Pages restraints, this version of the book is not rendered anywhere
      online by &copyholder;. Thus, you will need to render it yourself.
      Follow the <ulink url="&lfs-qol-repo;">LFS QOL rendering
      instructions</ulink> in order to render the book yourself. You will need
      <ulink url="&blfs-svn;/general/git.html">Git</ulink> to clone the
      repository.
    </para>

    <para revision="systemd">
      This version of this book is meant for Systemd LFS systems. You probably
      have rendered this version of the book yourself.
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Building software</title>

    <para>
      Building software on LFS QOL is identical to how it's done in the
      LFS books. It goes without saying firstmost that you should have
      <envar>MAKEFLAGS</envar> set to save yourself a lot of time. This is
      useful for the <command>make</command> utility to use the amount of
      threads that you both want and have.
    </para>

<screen><userinput>export MAKEFLAGS='-jx'</userinput></screen>

    <para>
      Replace <option>x</option> with the amount of threads you have.
      You can check the amount of threads you have with:
    </para>

<screen><userinput>grep processor /proc/cpuinfo</userinput></screen>

    <important>
      <para>
        Make sure that you have enough RAM for your system!
        A general method is having 2.5G per thread that is thrown at
        <command>make</command>. For instance, if you want to use 6 threads,
        multiply 6 by 2.5 (which is 15), then make sure you have 15G of RAM.
        If you don't have that RAM, try and limit the threads you throw at
        <command>make</command>.
      </para>
    </important>

  </sect2>

</sect1>
