<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="organization" xreflabel="Organization">
  <?dbhtml filename="organization.html"?>


  <title>Organization</title>

  <para>
    This book is divided into the following parts:
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part I - Introduction</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part contains essential information which is needed to
    understand the rest of the book.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part II - General Libraries and Utilities</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers libraries and utilities that you may want or need. Many
    packages can depend on the packages covered within. It also covers
    toolchains for those that may need them.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part III - Servers</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers packages for setting up a server, which can include web
    hosting (major servers), mail server software, databases, and other stuff.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part IV - Graphical Components</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers graphical components that may be useful and help with
    debugging and testing or be useful in their own right.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part V - Window Managers, Compositors, and Desktop Environments</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers graphical environments you may wish to use.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part VI - Emulators</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers many emulators for computers, vide game consoles, and
    more.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part VII - General Gaming Software</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers gaming support software that is not covered in BLFS and
    GLFS.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Part VIII - SVR4</bridgehead>

  <para>
    This part covers SVR4 tooling and various software.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Appendices</bridgehead>

  <para>
    The Appendices present information which doesn't belong in the body of
    book; they are included as reference material. The glossary of acronyms
    is a handy feature.
  </para>

</sect1>
